多謝。
Hong Kong law to do so.
政府法案，首讀。
政府法案二讀，律政司司長。
作為一個金融或風險管理風險管理工具。
二零一六年仲裁及調解法例第三者資助資助修訂條例草案。
主席，我 move that the Arbitration and Mediation Legislation Third Party Funding Amendment Bill, 2016 be read the second time.
The Hong Kong courts do not object in principle to third-party funding of arbitration and related proceedings, including mediation.
政府有長遠的政策，促進香港作為領先的國際法律及爭議解決服務中心在亞太地區。
As there is uncertainty as to whether third-party funding of arbitration is permitted under the current Hong Kong law, the attractiveness of Hong Kong as a venue of arbitration may be affected.
的建議，May在《報告》上關於第三方撥款為仲裁，發表於《香港法律改革委員會》2016年10月，以及《調解委員會》的觀點。
在 recent years, third-party funding of arbitration and other dispute resolution proceedings has become increasingly common in various jurisdictions, including Australia, England and Wales, various European jurisdictions and the United States.
The main objective of the bill is to amend the arbitration ordinance, Cap Six Hundred Nine, and the mediation ordinance, Cap Six Two O, to clarify that third-party funding of arbitration, mediation and related proceedings is permitted under Hong Kong law. The proposed amendments were formulated on the basis.
Today, third-party funding arrangements have usually been motivated by a fund party's lack of financial resources to pursue its own claims in contentious proceedings. However, increasingly, parties who do have the financial resources to fund contentious proceedings may also seek third-party.
香港是其中一個主要國際仲裁中心。在亞太地區，它很有可能是參與在港舉行的仲裁的當事人，考慮是否應該尋求第三方資金來支持其參與該仲裁。如果這被明確允許，由香港。
然而，它目前尚不清晰，是否普通法的維持和補償原則也適用於香港的第三方仲裁資金。確實，事實上，一個最終上訴判決在2007年作出時，明確地留下了這個問題。
And associate proceedings under the arbitration ordinance.
expressed support for the introduction of the bill into the legislative.
With which third-party funders would ordinarily be expected to comply when carrying on the funding activities.
The new Part 10 Capital A, which is based on the draft provisions in the LRC report, contains six divisions.
This may also affect the competitiveness of Hong Kong as an arbitration centre in handling cross-border investment and commercial disputes.
The DOJ has also consulted the Steering Committee on Mediation, and the Steering Committee supported the proposed consequential amendments to the Mediation Ordinance.
In October 2015, the subcommittee published a consultation paper, proposing that third-party funding for arbitration taking place in Hong Kong should be permitted under Hong Kong law.
政府認為，從促進香港作為國際調解中心的角度，以及釐清法律的目的，提出法律改革是可取的。
The LLC also recommended that consideration should be given to whether to make consequential amendments at the same time to the mediation ordinance to extend the above proposals to mediation within the scope of the mediation ordinance.
It is important that Hong Kong, as one of the leading centres for international legal and dispute resolution services in the Asia-Pacific region, can keep up with the latest international development and thereby enhance its competitive position.
The bill proposes that a new Part 10 Capital A be added to the arbitration ordinance, so as to ensure that third-party funding of arbitration is not prohibited by the common law doctrines of maintenance and chimpity, and to provide for related measures and safeguards.
Against the above background, I, together with the Chief Justice, asked the LRC in June 2013 to set up a committee to review the current position relating to third-party funding of arbitration for the purpose of considering whether reform is needed.
Based on the submissions received during the public consultation period, the LRC published the report in October 2016, concluding that the reform of Hong Kong law is needed to state that the common law doctrines of maintenance and chimpity do not prevent third-party funding of arbitration.
The LRC recommended that third-party funders funding arbitration should be required to comply with a code of practice issued by a body authorised under the arbitration ordinance. The code should also set out the standards, including financial and ethical standards and practices.
議員議案。
在發展立法。
for non-Hong Kong mediation.
我現在向各位提出嘅代議議題係。
With these remarks, I urge members to support the bill. Thank you, President.
There is undoubtedly a trend to permit party funding of arbitration in international arbitration.
這是 to facilitate the preparatory work for developing regulatory framework to be done before the provisions clarifying the legal position come into operation.
We believe that the bill, when enacted, will further enhance Hong Kong's position as a leading centre for international legal and dispute resolution services in the Asia-Pacific region.
二零一六年仲裁及調解法例第三者資助修訂條例草案予以議讀，按照議事規則辯論現在中止待續，條例草案交由內務委員會處理。
Under the above proposal, where litigation in court ensued despite the mediation, the doctrines of maintenance and chancery will continue to apply. The doctrines will only be inapplicable to the mediation conducted prior to or during the course of the litigation.
The new part ten capital, sorry, the new parts ten capital A is intended to come into operation in two stages. Divisions one, two, four and six will commence on the gazetteer of the ordinance, while divisions three and five will commence on a date to be appointed.
Following the release of the report, the Department of Justice (DOJ) has written to key legal and arbitration professional bodies in Hong Kong to consult them on the recommendations set out in the report. The organisations which have responded so far have all indicated their support for the proposed reforms.
在The Meeting of the Panel on Administration of Justice and Legal Services, the AJLS Panel of the Legislative Council held in November last year, I together with the Chairperson of the Subcommittee provided a briefing on the proposed reform and the views of the aforementioned stakeholders. The Panel
The bill also proposes that a new section seven A be added to the mediation ordinance, so as to extend the application of the new part ten A of the arbitration ordinance to mediation to which the mediation ordinance applies, and to funding of services provided in Hong Kong.
主席，The D.O.J. has been reviewing the dispute resolution regime of Hong Kong from time to time, and will also consider improvement to the arbitration ordinance and the mediation ordinance as and when appropriate, so as to ensure that the latest developments in the dispute resolution sector can be promptly reflected.